Robert Porter Patterson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Under Secretary of War Files, 1940-1945 (Box 107-211)
  - Army and navy
    - Contract Board
    - Munitions Board, (4 folders)
  - Army Service Forces (Box 115)
    - Procurement conference, Chicago, Ill.
    - Services of supply
  - Army Specialists Corps
  - Army Specialized Training Program, (2 folders) (Box 116)
  - Army Supply Program
  - Assistant secretary of war, John J. McCloy
  - Athletics
  - Atomic bomb, (2 folders)
  - Atrocities
  - Australia
  - Automotive industry
  - Awards, (2 folders)
  - "A" miscellaneous, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 117)
  - Bendix Aviation Corp.
  - Birthday Greetings
  - Bishop Joseph Warren, Jr., (2 folders)
  - Blackouts
  - Blossom, Francis
  - Boards and committees
  - British
    - Armament plant expansion
    - Economic policy in war
    - Organization for war production
  - Budget and Financial Administration
  - "B" miscellaneous, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 118)
  - Canada
  - Caribbean Highway
  - Carter, Colonel A. H. (Box 119)
  - Cavalry
  - Certificates, tax, etc. (Second Revenue Act 1940)
  - Chaplain Corps
  - Chemical Warfare Service, (3 folders)
  - China
  - Civil Affairs Division
  - Civil Defense, (3 folders)
  - Civilian employees
  - Claims, (2 folders)
  - Clark, Grenville
  - Clemency Board
  - Coal (Box 120)
    - General
    - Labor strike, (2 folders)
  - Combined Chiefs of Staff
  - Combined Production and Resources Board
  - Command and General Staff School, Fort Leavenworth, Kans.
  - Commanding General
  - Commissions in U.S. Army, (2 folders)
  - Committee on Shipping
  - Committee on War Agency Representatives
  - Commodities
    - Copper
    - Miscellaneous (Box 121)
    - Nickel
    - Rubber
    - Steel
    - Strategic materials
  - Commodities Division
  - Community War Fund Campaign
  - Conferences, (5 folders)
  - Congested Production Areas, (3 folders) (Box 122)
  - Conservation
  - Construction, (5 folders)
  - Construction Division, (2 folders) (Box 123)
  - Construction reports, ordnance plants
  - Contract Appeals and Adjustments Board
  - Contracts, (7 folders); (5 folders) (Box 124, Box 125)
  - Control
  - Control Council for Germany
  - Controlled materials plan, (1 folder) (Box 126)
  - Conversion
  - Copper, (1 folder) (Box 127)
  - Coordination Committee
  - Correspondence, handling of
  - Cost-Plus-A-Fixed-Fee contracts, (2 folders)
  - Cotton
  - Crowell, Benedict
  - Court martial cases, (2 folders)
  - Curtiss-Wright Co.
  - "C" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box 128)
  - Decorations
  - Deferments
  - Delegated duties (Box 129)
  - Demobilization, (3 folders)
  - Directives, (2 folders)
  - Director of procurement
  - Director of production
  - Director, Women's Army Auxiliary Corp., press conference
  - Disciplinary barracks and rehabilitation centers
  - Distribution Division
  - Dumbarton Oaks Conference, Washington, D.C.
  - "D" miscellaneous, (5 folders) (Box 130)
  - Economic Defense Board
  - Economic Welfare Board
  - Efficiency
  - Engineer Corps, (2 folders)
  - Enlistment figures
  - Everett, C. W.
  - "E" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Facility Clearance Board (Box 131)
  - Federal airport program
  - Field artillery
  - Fiscal Division, (2 folders)
  - Food administration, (2 folders)
  - Football
  - Ford contract
  - Foreign Petroleum Committee (Box 132)
  - Fort Myer, Va., exhibit
  - France
  - Fuel Oil Committee
  - "F" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
  - Gas masks
  - General depots
  - General staff, (5 folders)
  - Germany (Box 133)
  - Gliders
  - Great Britain
  - Greece
  - Ground forces
  - Guadacanal
  - Guiberson Engine, (2 folders)
  - "G" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
  - G-4
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass. (Box 134)
  - Hawaii
  - Hotel accommodation for soldiers
  - Housing, (3 folders)
  - "H" miscellaneous, (5 folders)
  - Industrial Mobilization Plan (Box 135)
  - Infantry
  - Information and education
  - Inspection trips
  - Inspector general
  - Insurance, (3 folders)
  - Internal Security Division
  - Inventions
  - Inventories
  - Investigations, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 136)
  - Ireland
  - Italy
  - "I" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Japanese
  - Jewel bearings survey, (2 folders)
  - Jobs, (4 folders)
  - Joint Army and Navy Committee on Welfare and Recreation
  - Joint Contract Termination Board, (2 folders) (Box 137)
  - Joint Price Adjustment Board, (3 folders)
  - Joint Production Survey Committee, (2 folders)
  - Joint Raw Materials Board, (2 folders)
  - Joint War Production Committee, United States and Canada, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 138)
  - Judge Advocate General, (3 folders)
  - Justice Department, (2 folders)
  - "J" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - "K" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box 139)
  - Labor
    - General, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 140, Box 141)
    - Absenteeism
    - Aircraft shortage, (2 folders) (Box 142)
    - Contracts
    - Morale
    - S. A. Woods Co.
    - Unemployment, New York, N.Y.
    - Wage stabilization
  - Land acquisition, (2 folders)
  - Legislation, (2 folders) (Box 143)
  - Legal and Liaison Division
  - Lend-Lease, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 144)
  - Libraries
  - List
  - Lumber
  - "L" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
  - Machine tools, (2 folders) (Box 145)
  - Mafoliata
  - Magnesium, (2 folders)
  - Maneuvers
  - Man-Power Section
  - Mead Committee
  - Meat
  - Medals
  - Medical Corps
  - Memoranda (Box 146)
    - Personal
    - Nos. 1-500, (5 folders)
    - Nos. 500-700, (2 folders) (Box 147)
  - Motor Maintenance Corps
  - Munitions Assignments Board
  - Munitions objective
  - Munitions program
  - "M" miscellaneous, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 148)
  - National Board for Promotion Rifle Practice
  - National Defense Act
  - National defense migration
  - National Power Policy Committee, (2 folders)
  - National service, (2 folders) (Box 149)
  - Navy Department, (3 folders)
  - Negroes, (4 folders)
  - New facilities, (1 folder) (Box 150)
  - Nickel
  - North American Aviation, strike
  - Nurses, (2 folders)
  - "N" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Official correspondence (Box 151)
    - A-M, (13 folders)
    - Mc-Z, (11 folders) (Box 152)
  - Office memoranda
  - Office War Mobilization, (2 folders) (Box 153)
  - Office of War Mobilization and Reconversion, (7 folders)
  - Officer plan
  - Officers Service Committee
  - Operations Division
  - Ordnance (Box 154)
    - General, (7 folders)
    - Armor plate, Scranton, Pa., (2 folders) (Box 155)
    - Ammunition, (2 folders)
    - Defense plants, (2 folders)
    - Guns, (2 folders)
    - Tanks, (2 folders)
  - Ordnance Department
  - Organization For National Defense
  - "O" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 156)
  - Patents
  - Pearl Harbor report
  - Pentagon building
  - Personal Affairs Division
  - Personnel, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 157)
  - Petroleum, (4 folders); (9 folders); (8 folders) (Box 158, Box 159)
  - Photographs, (2 folders)
  - Piers
  - Planning Branch, (2 folders)
  - Plants (Box 160)
    - Expansion
    - General
    - Inspectorate
    - Protection, (2 folders)
    - Shutdowns
    - Site Board
    - Termination
  - Post Exchange Services
  - Post war
    - Planning
    - Policy, (1 folder) (Box 161)
  - Power, (3 folders)
  - Press criticisms
  - Price Adjustment Board, (3 folders); (8 folders) (Box 162)
  - Price administration
  - Price control (Box 163)
  - Priorities, (2 folders)
  - Prisoners of war, (2 folders)
  - Procurement
    - Army and navy
    - Distribution (Box 164)
    - Planning bulletin
    - Regulations
  - Production
    - Conference, (2 folders)
    - Director
    - Division
    - General
    - Requirements Plan
    - Scheduling
    - Spot Authorization
    - Urgency Committee (Box 165)
    - Working Hours
  - Program determinations, War Production Board
  - Provost Marshal General
  - Public Relations, (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box 166)
  - Purchase and Contract Section, (2 folders)
  - Purchase Policy Advisory Committee
  - Purchases
  - Purchases Division
  - "P" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
  - Quartermaster, (6 folders) (Box 167)
  - "Q" miscellaneous
  - Rations
  - Raw Materials Board
  - Real Estate, (2 folders)
  - Recommendations
  - Reconstruction Finance Corp., (2 folders)
  - Redeployment
    - Equipment
    - Troops
  - Refugee Committee
  - Regular officers
  - Reorganization, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 168)
  - Reparations Commission
  - Reports to be rendered by Services of Supply
  - Requirements and Resources
  - Requisitioning property, (2 folders)
  - Reserve Officers, (2 folders)
  - Resources and Production Division
  - Rifles, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 169)
  - Rubber, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 170)
  - Russia
  - "R" miscellaneous, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 171)
  - Salvage
  - School of Military Government, Charlottesville, Va., (4 folders)
  - Scientific research and development
  - Second Revenue Act
  - Secretary of war, (4 folders)
  - Selective service, (2 folders) (Box 172)
  - Service commands
  - Seventy-seventh Division
  - Shutdowns
  - Signal Corps, (3 folders)
  - Small business
  - Soldier voting
  - Space, (2 folders)
  - Special services, (2 folders)
  - Standby plants
  - State Department (Box 173)
  - State laws
  - State taxes
  - State and local government coordination
  - Statistics, (3 folders)
  - Steel, (4 folders)
  - Stimson, Henry L.
  - Stockpiles
  - Strikes, (1 folder) (Box 174)
  - Sub-Committee on Appropriations
  - Subcontracting, (2 folders)
  - Supply Control System
  - Supply Priorities and Allocations Board
  - Surgeon general
  - Surplus property, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 175)
  - Survey
    - Cincinnati, Ohio
    - New York, N.Y.
  - "S" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 176)
  - Tankers
  - Tax amortization, (3 folders)
  - Taxes
  - Technical Industrial Intelligence Committee
  - Telephones, (3 folders)
  - Tort claims
  - Trade treaties
  - Training
  - Transportation (Box 177)
    - Convention meetings
    - Council of State Governments
    - General
    - Motor, (2 folders)
    - Railroad
    - Report
    - Section, (4 folders) (Box 178)
    - Shipping
  - Treasury Department, (3 folders)
  - Trips, (4 folders)
  - Truman Committee, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 179)
  - "T" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Under Secretary of War
  - Universal military training, (2 folders)
  - "U" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Veterans reemployment (Box 180)
  - "V" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - War and postwar adjustment policies
  - War Contracts Price Adjustment Board
  - War department supply system
  - War Manpower Commission, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 181, Box 182, Box 183)
  - War Mobilization Office (Box 184)
  - War Production Board, (4 folders)
  - Welfare and recreation
  - Weldon Springs project (Box 185)
  - White House, (3 folders)
  - Women's Army Corps
  - World war
  - Working hours
  - Wright Aeronautical Corp.
  - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (7 folders)
  - Miscellany (Box 186-187)
  - Speeches, (11 folders) (Box 188)
  - Card indices (Box 189)
    - Aug. 1940-May 1941
      - A-C
      - D-Lansing (Box 190)
      - Laporte-Q (Box 191)
      - R-Z (Box 192)
    - May 1941-1942 (Box 193)
      - Al-De
      - Do-Li (Box 194)
      - Lo-R (Box 195)
      - Re-Z (Box 196)
    - 9 Mar. 1942-31 Dec. 1943 (Box 197)
      - A-Bru
      - Ca-Em (Box 198)
      - Fa-Ja (Box 199)
      - Jo-Mos (Box 200)
      - Na-Pa (Box 201)
      - Re-Str (Box 202)
      - Ta-Z (Box 203)
    - 1 Jan. 1944-1945 (Box 204)
      - A-Ci
      - Co-He (Box 205)
      - Ho-Mc (Box 206)
      - N-S (Box 207)
      - Se-Z (Box 208)
  - Card abstracts of correspondence (Box 209)
    - A-G
    - H-O (Box 210)
    - P-Z (Box 211)
- 2023 Addition, 1947-1952 (Box 212-216)
  Bound volumes of outgoing correspondence, documenting Patterson's professional activities in the latter years of his career, and speeches and statements given during and after his tenure as secretary of war.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Correspondence, bound
    - 1947, Oct.-1948, Apr., Oct. 1947-Apr. 1948 (Box 212)
    - 1949, Jan.-Aug., Jan.-Aug. 1949 (Box 212)
    - 1949, July-Dec., July-Dec. 1949 (Box 213)
    - 1950, Jan.-June, Jan.-June 1950 (Box 213)
    - 1950, Jul.-Dec., Jul.-Dec. 1950 (Box 214)
    - 1951, Jan.-June, Jan.-June 1951 (Box 214)
    - 1951, July-1952, Jan., July 1951-Jan. 1952 (Box 215)
  - Speeches and statements
    - 1945, Sept.-1946, Dec., Sept. 1945-Dec. 1946; (2 folders) (Box 215)
    - 1947 (Box 215)
    - 1949, Jan.-1950, June, Jan. 1949-June 1950 (Box 216)
- Classified, 1941-1943 (Box CL 1)
  Correspondence, memoranda, and notes.
  Organized and described according to the series, folders, and containers from which the items were removed.
  - Under Secretary of War Files (Box CL1)
    - Civil Affairs Division (Container 119)